Welche jüdischen Feiertage sind für Dich besonders wichtig, wenn es um Exil, Freiheit und Gerechtigkeit geht?
We have plenty of holidays that have
Symbols of reminding us of
the exile of Egypt.
Because it was,
It is considered to be
one of the main things in Judaism,
This is very interesting,
because the exodus of Egypt
shows you, how Jewish people
treat
Freedom.
Why is it so difficult for me as a Jewish person,
to see other people enslaved like that?
If you think about it there were plagues in Egypt.
How many plagues were there,
you remember? It was 10 plagues.
Yet it was after the 8th or the 9th,
that Pharaoh told Moses
"Get your people and"...
"Take your people and get the hell out of here"
But yet there was a 10th plague,
the most horrific one.
What was it for? Moses said to Pharaoh,
"I will take till the last horses of your stables"
"Everyone that is being enslaved by you will walk free"
"when the Jewish people walk free"
And, that is the Jewish standard.